# Olena Listratova

web developer / olena.listratova@gmail.com / https://carrot-e.github.io/

The question of top importance for me is user experience. In my opinion any developer should first think of the way the product will be used and only after that – about how a feature can be implemented.

#### My skillset

My everyday stack is:

PHP

JS (jQuery, Vue.js)

**HTML** 

CSS (Less, Sass)

Smarty

MySQL Git

Linux

I have some experience with:

ElasticSearch

Gulp

Node.js

Docker

## Experience

May 2016 - Present

Lead front-end developer at IT Craft

As a front-end lead developer I've organised and participated in a huge redesign process. In three months we implemented a brand-new mobile-friendly, rewritten almost from scratch UI.

At this position my responsibilities included not only development and bug-fixing, but also participation in requirements discussions (with remote designer and product owner), planning and code quality control. This position combined things I am most passionate about: UI and UX deliberations, modern front-end technologies and management tasks.

Jul 2013 - May 2016

Web developer at IT Craft

I worked as a full stack developer on a professional social network product.

One of my best achievements was a significant improvement of one of the core system modules. The solution proposed and implemented by me was so flexible and re-usable that shortly became the de facto standard in the team.

Also I have some experience in knowledge sharing: I participated in internships organised in my company as lecturer and mentor.

## Foreign Languages

English: upper-intermediate

#### Education

Simon Kuznets Kharkiv National University of Economics 2010 – 2014: Bachelor's Degree, Multimedia Technologies